<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Krolyxon&#39;s site</title>
    <link>/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Krolyxon&#39;s site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:12:28 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Abandoning Music</title>
      <link>/posts/abandoning-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:12:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/abandoning-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ladies and Gentlemen it is with great pleasure to inform all of you that i have finally decided to get rid of all the music from my life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-thoughts-on-music&#34;&gt;My thoughts on Music&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I Love music. It can be a great tool if you use it in your life just to entertain yourself once in a while and relax. But for me, the story is quite different, lets start with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Experience With Dopamine Detox</title>
      <link>/posts/experience-with-dopamine-detox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 14:55:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/experience-with-dopamine-detox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-experience-with-dopamine-detox&#34;&gt;My Experience with Dopamine Detox&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few days ago i came to realize that from past few months i haven&amp;rsquo;t had any creative thoughts and i hadn&amp;rsquo;t done anything new at all. It was all the same, wake up, music, watch movies, videos on youtube, consume consume&amp;hellip;..&#xA;I would spend all my day just consuming information on the internet and not doing any real work. My mind was being stimulated entire day, whether it be with music or youtube videos.&#xA;i wouldn&amp;rsquo;t spend a single moment of my day without any kind of stimulation. Sleeping? just play a long youtube video and fall asleep listening to it. Getting ready for college? just play a music playlist in the background. Working out? just play workout playlist. Reading or studying a article? play Lofi music in background. this had a big impact on my creativity and thinking.&#xA;it was depressing, because when i was younger i was one of the most creative kids among other students in school, here i am being a coomer on the internet doing nothing but consuming online media.&#xA;I decided to work on my lifestyle, and started dopamine detox, its been a week, and today i am going to share my experience with my dopamine detox.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
