<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:12:28 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Abandoning Music</title>
      <link>/posts/abandoning-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:12:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/abandoning-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ladies and Gentlemen it is with great pleasure to inform all of you that i have finally decided to get rid of all the music from my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-thoughts-on-music&#34;&gt;My thoughts on Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I Love music. It can be a great tool if you use it in your life just to entertain yourself once in a while and relax. But for me, the story is quite different, lets start with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Ladies and Gentlemen it is with great pleasure to inform all of you that i have finally decided to get rid of all the music from my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-thoughts-on-music&#34;&gt;My thoughts on Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I Love music. It can be a great tool if you use it in your life just to entertain yourself once in a while and relax. But for me, the story is quite different, lets start with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to listen to it every single day, not spending single bit of free time without listening to music. The first thing i would do when i wake up is to start my favorite playlist and then start getting ready, i had gotten used to doing my daily chores or any kind of work to be honest while having music being played in the background. It was as if like my life was a movie at this point and that music was the background music being played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this had become a problem, i couldn&amp;rsquo;t find myself being productive at all without having music in my background. It was as if music was the only source of motivation at that point and i started noticing that.
The amount of dopamine hits good music can give you is unimaginable, especially if the music is from Hans Zimmer, he is too good and you just can&amp;rsquo;t help but listen to it for hours and hours. While i still don&amp;rsquo;t think music is a bad thing, but in my case things have gone wrong, really wrong. So i got no option but to abandon it from my daily routine. I have made strict rules about when i am allowed to listen to music (which is never, by myself). The only way i am allowed to listen to music is when i am with my associates and he/she is listening to it, so i might join them but i am not allowed to play it by myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully i didn&amp;rsquo;t have any digital footprint of the music i listen to because i never used Spotify and any other online music streaming services, i didn&amp;rsquo;t have to spend any time deleting online accounts, just had to &lt;code&gt;rm -rf ~/music &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo pacman -Rns mpd rmptui&lt;/code&gt;, and there it is, Its Gone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its ironic that i am writing this blog called &amp;ldquo;Abandoning Music&amp;rdquo; even though i myself have created a TUI music player previously (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/krolyxon/rmptui&#34;&gt;rmptui&lt;/a&gt;, now archived). I guess i am also abandoning the development on it as well. Anyways, as of today (16/12/2024) the latest commit on that repo was 6 months ago, so i think its abandoned already 😅.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;should-you-do-the-same&#34;&gt;Should you do the same?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really think so. If you only occasionally listen to it and not have it playing in the background all the time as if its a part of your daily routine, you are doing just fine. Enjoy it, its good for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switched to Brave</title>
      <link>/posts/switched-to-brave/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 13:56:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/switched-to-brave/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-switched-to-brave-browser-from-librewolf&#34;&gt;I switched to Brave Browser from Librewolf&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright i have been making alot of switches these days, first it was switching to NvChad now this.
I previously used Librewolf, which was a more privacy focused browser based on Firefox, and to be honest it worked quite well.
It supported all the extensions/addons i needed, it had firefox sync, and the overall experience was nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that was bugging me was performance, previously i was unaware that librewolf performed worse compared to other chromium based browser.
I had to install a chromium based browser for my college work for some time, and there i experienced some speed, real speed.
And i fell into the trap and now i am using a chromium based browser as my default browser. There are lots of things that i am missing from librewolf,
such as smooth scrolling and mouse gestures (i miss them), its UI and firefox sync, but speed is something i always prioritize over anything else, so brave it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-switched-to-brave-browser-from-librewolf&#34;&gt;I switched to Brave Browser from Librewolf&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright i have been making alot of switches these days, first it was switching to NvChad now this.
I previously used Librewolf, which was a more privacy focused browser based on Firefox, and to be honest it worked quite well.
It supported all the extensions/addons i needed, it had firefox sync, and the overall experience was nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that was bugging me was performance, previously i was unaware that librewolf performed worse compared to other chromium based browser.
I had to install a chromium based browser for my college work for some time, and there i experienced some speed, real speed.
And i fell into the trap and now i am using a chromium based browser as my default browser. There are lots of things that i am missing from librewolf,
such as smooth scrolling and mouse gestures (i miss them), its UI and firefox sync, but speed is something i always prioritize over anything else, so brave it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, one nice thing about brave (or any other chromium based browser) is that you can have multiple profiles. Now i can have separate profiles for different use cases.
One profile for College, one for personal stuff, one for work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, the experience on brave has been satisfactory and i don&amp;rsquo;t plan to switch to any other browser anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switched to Nvchad</title>
      <link>/posts/switched-to-nvchad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/switched-to-nvchad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-officially-switched-to-nvchad&#34;&gt;I officially switched to NvChad&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my journey of using Neovim, i always avoided using a pre-built config or any distribution of neovim such as LunarVim or AtroVim.
I felt pride in building my own configuration. But, after spending countless amount of painful hours fixing things manually when some plugin decides to make some breaking changes out of nowhere.
I finally decided i would just switch to a pre-built config like Lazyvim or NvChad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-officially-switched-to-nvchad&#34;&gt;I officially switched to NvChad&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my journey of using Neovim, i always avoided using a pre-built config or any distribution of neovim such as LunarVim or AtroVim.
I felt pride in building my own configuration. But, after spending countless amount of painful hours fixing things manually when some plugin decides to make some breaking changes out of nowhere.
I finally decided i would just switch to a pre-built config like Lazyvim or NvChad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially i tried, Lazyvim but i didn&amp;rsquo;t like it that much so i ended up using NvChad and to be honest its been a fun experience, everything just works out of the box.
My muscle memory goes well with this configuration, since the configuration i used previously, which i made myself was very similar and inspired by NvChad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration is hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/krolyxon/nvim&#34;&gt;krolyxon/nvim&lt;/a&gt; and the old configuration is available in the same repo in a different &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/krolyxon/nvim/tree/old&#34;&gt;branch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rmptui - MPD client in Rust</title>
      <link>/posts/rmptui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 19:38:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rmptui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-all-began&#34;&gt;How it all began&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that i have been working on for last couple of weeks.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/krolyxon/rmptui&#34;&gt;rmptui&lt;/a&gt; is a tui music player whichworks with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.musicpd.org/&#34;&gt;MPD&lt;/a&gt; (Music Player Daemon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had decided to make a music player in rust in the May of 2023, but i never got around to it.
It was two months ago when i actually started working on it, because i wanted to learn rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmptui-v0.1.4.png&#34; alt=&#34;rmptui-v0.1.4&#34;&gt;
Above pictures shows the directory browser tab of rmptui.
It has total three tabs:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-all-began&#34;&gt;How it all began&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that i have been working on for last couple of weeks.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/krolyxon/rmptui&#34;&gt;rmptui&lt;/a&gt; is a tui music player whichworks with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.musicpd.org/&#34;&gt;MPD&lt;/a&gt; (Music Player Daemon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had decided to make a music player in rust in the May of 2023, but i never got around to it.
It was two months ago when i actually started working on it, because i wanted to learn rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmptui-v0.1.4.png&#34; alt=&#34;rmptui-v0.1.4&#34;&gt;
Above pictures shows the directory browser tab of rmptui.
It has total three tabs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Queue - Shows current playing queue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Directory browser - Lets you explore your music library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Playlists - Shows your playlists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get more info about keymaps from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/krolyxon/rmptui?tab=readme-ov-file#keys&#34;&gt;Github Readme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crates-used&#34;&gt;Crates Used&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So rmptui uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/mpd&#34;&gt;rust-mpd&lt;/a&gt; crate to interact with Music Player Daemon.
This crate is no longer maintained it seems, a lot of the commands are ambiguous,
and it was relatively annoying to work with it.
The better approach would be to just use TCP sockets, but anyways i found my ways to
work with this crate anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/ratatui&#34;&gt;ratatui&lt;/a&gt; for the TUI (Terminal User Interface)
which is a pretty lightweight and intuitive library to cook TUIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;state-of-rmptui-right-now-2024-06-02&#34;&gt;State of Rmptui right now (2024-06-02)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is still in its early development days, where a lot of bugs are expected, so i kindly request
everyone to report bugs on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/krolyxon/rmptui/issues&#34;&gt;Github Issues&lt;/a&gt;, so i can fix them.
Currently it is in its version 0.1.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-plans&#34;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now rmptui is not asynchronous and is single threaded, which is really bad for a music player
that interacts with a server and handles keybinds and renders TUI at the same time.
I also plan to add support for lyrics fetching in future.
Also the codebase is a giant clusterf*ck, so i hope to organize that as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not the least, release a stable v1.0.0 and public it on crates.io&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cpu Manufacturing Is Just Magic For Me</title>
      <link>/posts/cpu-manufacturing-is-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 17:42:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cpu-manufacturing-is-magic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-think-that-way&#34;&gt;Why i think that way.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching countless amount of videos on the internet about,
how Microchips/Microprocessors are manufactured. I still to this day just believe its just f*cking magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am aware of the steps and processes that are done to manufacture them, but
how the hell do you even do that bro???
like how the hell do you design 11 billion semiconductors in a silicon die that is just few millimeters in diameter.
holy shit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-think-that-way&#34;&gt;Why i think that way.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching countless amount of videos on the internet about,
how Microchips/Microprocessors are manufactured. I still to this day just believe its just f*cking magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am aware of the steps and processes that are done to manufacture them, but
how the hell do you even do that bro???
like how the hell do you design 11 billion semiconductors in a silicon die that is just few millimeters in diameter.
holy shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its amazing that you can produce materials having such high level of precision put into it. its just outright magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-videos&#34;&gt;Reference videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dX9CGRZwD-w&#34;&gt;Branch Education - How Microchips are Made?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2ehSCWoaOqQ&#34;&gt;LTT Intel Fab Tour&lt;/a&gt; - This honestly blew me away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experience With Dopamine Detox</title>
      <link>/posts/experience-with-dopamine-detox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 14:55:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/experience-with-dopamine-detox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-experience-with-dopamine-detox&#34;&gt;My Experience with Dopamine Detox&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few days ago i came to realize that from past few months i haven&amp;rsquo;t had any creative thoughts and i hadn&amp;rsquo;t done anything new at all. It was all the same, wake up, music, watch movies, videos on youtube, consume consume&amp;hellip;..
I would spend all my day just consuming information on the internet and not doing any real work. My mind was being stimulated entire day, whether it be with music or youtube videos.
i wouldn&amp;rsquo;t spend a single moment of my day without any kind of stimulation. Sleeping? just play a long youtube video and fall asleep listening to it. Getting ready for college? just play a music playlist in the background. Working out? just play workout playlist. Reading or studying a article? play Lofi music in background. this had a big impact on my creativity and thinking.
it was depressing, because when i was younger i was one of the most creative kids among other students in school, here i am being a coomer on the internet doing nothing but consuming online media.
I decided to work on my lifestyle, and started dopamine detox, its been a week, and today i am going to share my experience with my dopamine detox.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-experience-with-dopamine-detox&#34;&gt;My Experience with Dopamine Detox&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few days ago i came to realize that from past few months i haven&amp;rsquo;t had any creative thoughts and i hadn&amp;rsquo;t done anything new at all. It was all the same, wake up, music, watch movies, videos on youtube, consume consume&amp;hellip;..
I would spend all my day just consuming information on the internet and not doing any real work. My mind was being stimulated entire day, whether it be with music or youtube videos.
i wouldn&amp;rsquo;t spend a single moment of my day without any kind of stimulation. Sleeping? just play a long youtube video and fall asleep listening to it. Getting ready for college? just play a music playlist in the background. Working out? just play workout playlist. Reading or studying a article? play Lofi music in background. this had a big impact on my creativity and thinking.
it was depressing, because when i was younger i was one of the most creative kids among other students in school, here i am being a coomer on the internet doing nothing but consuming online media.
I decided to work on my lifestyle, and started dopamine detox, its been a week, and today i am going to share my experience with my dopamine detox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rules-for-dopamine-detox&#34;&gt;Rules for Dopamine Detox&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No music while doing daily chores or work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No social media, unless your friend tells you to watch some reel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend at least 30 minutes reading a real book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even after you relapse. don&amp;rsquo;t get depressed,  just restart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend some time of the day doing nothing, that time you will have the most creative thoughts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t do this for set amount of days, from now on this is your lifestyle. Forever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consume less, produce more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do one and only task at a time, no multitasking. Things might take more time to get done, but at least you will get them done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-experience&#34;&gt;My Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day i started Dopamine detox, i woke up and avoided listening to music while getting ready, i was already getting quick at doing things done. i wouldn&amp;rsquo;t spend any time checking out social media or anything related to internet. i would just wake up, and start getting ready. Nothing else.
The whole day i was feeling like a wizard, i felt like i could get anything done. Be it homework, or any programming task, everything started to feel like i can do it.
My mind was calm, i got better at problem solving, i started getting more things done, and i felt like a god.
From last few days, this godly feeling hasn&amp;rsquo;t gotten away, and today i am writing this blog to share it with you all.
Guess what, i even made a cool &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/krolyxon/JavaCalc&#34;&gt;GUI calculator&lt;/a&gt; in Java (which i sucked at), i just sat down and did it, no constant stimulation in background, just work. My working speed has gotten insanely fast. i just feel like i can get done anything fast.
I dont feel like relapsing at all. I wish i had started living like this earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got Faulty Product From Flipkart</title>
      <link>/posts/got-faulty-product-from-flipkart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:18:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/got-faulty-product-from-flipkart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today i got a faulty 16GB ram from Flipkart.
So the RAM i ordered was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flipkart.com/crucial-16gb-ddr4-3200mhz-cl22-16-gb-laptop-ct16g4sfs832a/p/itmceac5769ac001?pid=RAMGKX6ZCJPDGCTZ&amp;amp;q=crucial&amp;#43;16&amp;#43;gb&amp;#43;laptop&amp;#43;ram&amp;amp;qH=6bd7dde490d2b5bc&#34;&gt;Crucial 16GB 3200Mhz laptop RAM&lt;/a&gt;. It turns out to be faulty and i cant even return it 💀.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is the story in the format of 4 stages of grief :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stage-1-excitement-happiness&#34;&gt;Stage 1: Excitement, Happiness.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it was 10 am in the morning, i was sleeping. I get a call from my mum that the RAM i ordered online has just arrived and i gotta be there to confirm the delivery and to verify that the product is right. I woke up immediately, in a rush without fixing my bed. i ran with happiness and excitement, and full of thoughts of what i am going to do after upgrading my laptop&amp;rsquo;s ram. Confirmed the order, took the RAM, went back to my room. I was happy. I was excited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Today i got a faulty 16GB ram from Flipkart.
So the RAM i ordered was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flipkart.com/crucial-16gb-ddr4-3200mhz-cl22-16-gb-laptop-ct16g4sfs832a/p/itmceac5769ac001?pid=RAMGKX6ZCJPDGCTZ&amp;amp;q=crucial&amp;#43;16&amp;#43;gb&amp;#43;laptop&amp;#43;ram&amp;amp;qH=6bd7dde490d2b5bc&#34;&gt;Crucial 16GB 3200Mhz laptop RAM&lt;/a&gt;. It turns out to be faulty and i cant even return it 💀.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is the story in the format of 4 stages of grief :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stage-1-excitement-happiness&#34;&gt;Stage 1: Excitement, Happiness.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it was 10 am in the morning, i was sleeping. I get a call from my mum that the RAM i ordered online has just arrived and i gotta be there to confirm the delivery and to verify that the product is right. I woke up immediately, in a rush without fixing my bed. i ran with happiness and excitement, and full of thoughts of what i am going to do after upgrading my laptop&amp;rsquo;s ram. Confirmed the order, took the RAM, went back to my room. I was happy. I was excited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stage-2-fear--shocked&#34;&gt;Stage 2: Fear , Shocked.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting back to my room, i started opening my laptop&amp;rsquo;s back which has small plus/star screws with a huge flat head screwdriver 💀. i managed to open all the screws and the back panel withing 10 minutes, i installed the ram. After that my laptop booted into my Arch Linux (btw) without any issues, and i was still happy. To confirm that the ram has been installed correctly, i quickly ran &lt;code&gt;neofetch&lt;/code&gt;, and this is where my happiness started turning into fear. the ram was still &lt;code&gt;8 Gb&lt;/code&gt;, when it should have been &lt;code&gt;8 + 16 = 24 Gb&lt;/code&gt;.
Thinking that i just installed it incorrectly, i tried all different variations again, such as swapping the ram slots, using only the new ram, and all that. but it still wasn&amp;rsquo;t working, and then i was sure that i just got an defected product. I was Afraid. I was Shocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stage-3-anger-tears&#34;&gt;Stage 3: Anger, Tears&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now since it was for sure that i had gotten an defected RAM, i quickly opened up Flipkart and tried to find the Return button, and it turns out that this particular seller did not provide any return policies. I am not sure 100%, but i do believe it did said that it provides return policies and then the seller changed it, but we cant say for sure. I was really panicking.
I called Flipkart customer support, and had a talk with the technician, and there he also confirmed that Flipkart cant help me since the product does not come under the refundable product&amp;rsquo;s category. then i knew for sure, I am f*cked.
I was Angry. I was Crying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stage-4-acceptance&#34;&gt;Stage 4: Acceptance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After fuming and crying for about an hour, and talking with my friends on Matrix about it. i finally had just accepted it, and decided to write a article on it to share my feelings. I was broken but i was okay.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>auto-cpufreq Is All You Need</title>
      <link>/posts/auto-cpufreq-is-all-you-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 18:34:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/auto-cpufreq-is-all-you-need/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, i got myself a laptop (a gaming one) for college work, and the battery life was fine on windows (which it came preinstalled with) because windows by default does battery power optimizations preserve battery life. When i installed Arch Linux on it, the battery life was disappointing.
On windows my laptop would last for about 3 hours and on the other hand on linux, it would barely reach 2 hours&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Recently, i got myself a laptop (a gaming one) for college work, and the battery life was fine on windows (which it came preinstalled with) because windows by default does battery power optimizations preserve battery life. When i installed Arch Linux on it, the battery life was disappointing.
On windows my laptop would last for about 3 hours and on the other hand on linux, it would barely reach 2 hours&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tlp&#34;&gt;TLP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So i searched up on arch wiki on battery life optimizations on linux, and i came to know about &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/TLP&#34;&gt;TLP&lt;/a&gt; which is a feature-rich command line utility for saving battery power. So i used it, and it didnt really make a big difference&amp;hellip; i don&amp;rsquo;t know why, and i also didn&amp;rsquo;t go really deep into it. I probably got half an hour extra, thats all. Now, i know that TLP is not what i want, so i kept on search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;auto-cpufreq&#34;&gt;Auto-cpufreq&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then after digging online for few more hours, i got introduced to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AdnanHodzic/auto-cpufreq&#34;&gt;auto-cpufreq&lt;/a&gt;. It is a tool which automatically tinkers your CPU speed and optimizes power. I thought of giving it a try, and holy shit its amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation-of-auto-cpufreq&#34;&gt;Installation of Auto-cpufreq&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The installation is simple, all you have to do is clone their git repo and use their install script to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;git clone --depth&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; https://github.com/AdnanHodzic/auto-cpufreq.git
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;cd auto-cpufreq
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo ./auto-cpufreq-installer
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that would do the installation of auto-cpufreq, however to setup auto-cpufreq for your cpu and auto configure it, you have to run &lt;code&gt;sudo auto-cpufreq --install&lt;/code&gt; and then just reboot your laptop. And thats it.
To check if its working, just do &lt;code&gt;auto-cpufreq --stats&lt;/code&gt; and it will show the changes in cpu&amp;rsquo;s frequency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After setting up auto-cpufreq, my battery life is as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before: 2-2.5 Hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After: 4-4.5 Hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syncing keepass database between android and desktop with rsync</title>
      <link>/posts/sync-keepass-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sync-keepass-database/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-to-keepass&#34;&gt;Introduction to keepass&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone should use password managers, because remembering unique passwords is difficult.
There are many great password FOSS password managers such as bitwarden, keepass, keepassxc etc.
I wouldnt recommend using bitwarden because its cloud based,
Your password database is being stored in cloud, and it makes me really paranoid.
because there are thousands of users using it, so a lot of hackers trying to hack bitwarden&amp;rsquo;s server.
bitwarden allows you to self-host it, so you can host it in your own server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-to-keepass&#34;&gt;Introduction to keepass&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone should use password managers, because remembering unique passwords is difficult.
There are many great password FOSS password managers such as bitwarden, keepass, keepassxc etc.
I wouldnt recommend using bitwarden because its cloud based,
Your password database is being stored in cloud, and it makes me really paranoid.
because there are thousands of users using it, so a lot of hackers trying to hack bitwarden&amp;rsquo;s server.
bitwarden allows you to self-host it, so you can host it in your own server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you know, your boy is still paranoid. So i will go with keepassxc because its completely offlilne.
You can read the installation instructions and read more about it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://keepassxc.org&#34;&gt;keepassxc.org&lt;/a&gt;
However, we are going focus more about how to sync the password database created from keepassxc on
your desktop and cellphone(android).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you are done installing keepassxc on your desktop,
install &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.keepassdx.com/&#34;&gt;keepassdx&lt;/a&gt; on your cellphone,
To access your encrypted password database from your cellphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sync-the-database-between-both-devices&#34;&gt;Sync the database between both devices.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://rsync.samba.org/&#34;&gt;rsync&lt;/a&gt; and ssh(obviously&amp;hellip;) on your desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install termux on your cellphone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install &lt;code&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;openssh&lt;/code&gt; on termux by running &lt;code&gt;pkg install openssh rsync&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start ssh server on termux by running &lt;code&gt;sshd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get your local ip adress of your cellphone by running &lt;code&gt;ifconfig&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are done with that, go to the terminal on your desktop and run this command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;rsync -vrP --delete --rsh&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;ssh -p 8022&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; ~/passdb/on/desktop.kbdx username@ip:passdb/on/cellphone.kbdx 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;here i specify the port with &lt;code&gt;--rsh=&#39;ssh -p 8022&#39;&lt;/code&gt; because specifying it with &lt;code&gt;--port&lt;/code&gt; flag didng work for me.
repace your username with your username and local ip adress of termux in &lt;code&gt;username@ip&lt;/code&gt;.
and repace the paths in the commands to where your password database is stored in your desktop and cellphone.
and here we go, it will sync the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, i wanted to go further and make it a bit &lt;em&gt;automaticish&lt;/em&gt;, so i ended up with this script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;#!/bin/sh
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# paths of database file locations in android and desktop&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;anpath&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;storage/shared/path/to/pass-database.kdbx&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;deskpath&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;path/to/pass-database.kdbx&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# getting last modified date&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;desktop&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;stat -c%Y $deskpath&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;android&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;ssh android -t stat -c%Y $anpath&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# syncing the database between both devices by calculating&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# in which device the password database was last modified.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# not syncing anything if there was no change.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; $android -lt $desktop &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  echo &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;transferring from desktop to android&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  rsync -vrtP $deskpath android:$anpath 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;elif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; $desktop -lt $android &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  echo &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;transferring from android to desktop&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  rsync -vrtP android:$anpath $deskpath
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;elif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; $desktop -eq $android &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  echo &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;nothing was modified, not syncing&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When i run this script, it will check in which device i had the password database last modified,
and sync the password databse from desktop to cellphone if it was last modified on my desktop computer and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading my blog with bajillions of spelling &amp;amp; grammar mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to boot a computer without pressing power button</title>
      <link>/posts/turning-on-pc-without-power-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/turning-on-pc-without-power-button/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So recently, my computer&amp;rsquo;s power button stopped working.
i dont know what exactly happened to it, but it just stopped working.
now i was completely unable to boot my PC. i spent whole day without my computer,
thinking i would take it to a computer technician and fix it the next day.
but just for the sake of trying out, i tried figuring some way out myself.
I opened my PC&amp;rsquo;s cabinate and searched for the cable which connects the motherboard and the power button(POWER SW cable).
I disconnected that cable from the motherboard and took a screwdriver and then trouched it to the
pins where the POWER SW cable was connected previously.
Voilah! the pc booted up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;So recently, my computer&amp;rsquo;s power button stopped working.
i dont know what exactly happened to it, but it just stopped working.
now i was completely unable to boot my PC. i spent whole day without my computer,
thinking i would take it to a computer technician and fix it the next day.
but just for the sake of trying out, i tried figuring some way out myself.
I opened my PC&amp;rsquo;s cabinate and searched for the cable which connects the motherboard and the power button(POWER SW cable).
I disconnected that cable from the motherboard and took a screwdriver and then trouched it to the
pins where the POWER SW cable was connected previously.
Voilah! the pc booted up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem was it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t completely boot to my operating and
gave me an error that the POWER SW cable was disconnected, obviously because i removed it.
but it did gave me an option to go to the BIOS menu by pressing F2.
After going to the BIOS menu i went to the &amp;lsquo;Power Management&amp;rsquo; section and then &amp;lsquo;AC Recovery&amp;rsquo; and
changed the &amp;lsquo;Restore on AC Power Loss&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;Power On&amp;rsquo; (its &amp;lsquo;Power Off&amp;rsquo; by default.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if you just give electricity to your computer,
it will automatically turn on without the need of pressing the power button on your PC&amp;rsquo;s case/cabinet.
So now, i dont need to spend money to fix the power button and it saves me a little bit of time by not having
to press the power button everytime i want to turn on my pc.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lineage OS 19 on Moto g60</title>
      <link>/posts/lineageos-on-motorola/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lineageos-on-motorola/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;clean-android-experience&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Clean&amp;rsquo; Android experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As i have said in my home page, i dont use cell phones that much but i do own a moto g60,
because it has become impossible to live without a cell phone in this modern era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason i chose to buy a motorola phone instead of those sh*tty compenies like xiaomi, vivo, oppo etc.
was because my friend (well i dont have any, its just a ehh friend not friend friend) told me that Motorola phones are &amp;lsquo;privacy&amp;rsquo; friendly and provide clean android experience.
and yeah of course, i fell for it. And let me tell you, no its no way near &amp;lsquo;privacy&amp;rsquo; friendly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;clean-android-experience&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Clean&amp;rsquo; Android experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As i have said in my home page, i dont use cell phones that much but i do own a moto g60,
because it has become impossible to live without a cell phone in this modern era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason i chose to buy a motorola phone instead of those sh*tty compenies like xiaomi, vivo, oppo etc.
was because my friend (well i dont have any, its just a ehh friend not friend friend) told me that Motorola phones are &amp;lsquo;privacy&amp;rsquo; friendly and provide clean android experience.
and yeah of course, i fell for it. And let me tell you, no its no way near &amp;lsquo;privacy&amp;rsquo; friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only good thing was that it didnt come with preinstalled garbage,
its a good thing but you know you can always use &lt;code&gt;adb&lt;/code&gt; to remove any preinstalled app and it wont ever bother you,
unless you update your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyways, i tried using the default os it came with for a week or so. and to be honest,
it was horrible. it just didnt feel any different from something like MIUI,
yeah i do agree that its way cleaner but at the end i dont feel like i am private in any way.
so i asked for help in #gnulinuxindia in matrix. and one guy, i wish i remembered his name suggested me giving Lineage OS a try,
i went to it&amp;rsquo;s official website and looked for my model. yes, you guessed it right. it wasnt supported. but somehow i did find a guy on xda-developers.
This guy named Raghu Varma had built the ROM for moto g60. So i grabbed some tea and started following the installation steps and somehow managed to install it.
and god oh god, ITS AWESOMEEE!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using it for over a month now, and everything seems to work fine. yes it indeed is a little buggy, but i can work with it.
i also decided to root it after a week. problem is now i am unable to get OTA updates without messing up my root, so i just stopped updating.
But finally i am able to have some privacy on my device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;isnt this beautiful? i finally feel like i &amp;lsquo;own&amp;rsquo; my device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raghu Varma&amp;rsquo;s Lineage OS build: &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.xda-developers.com/t/rom-12l-hanoip-lineageos-19-1-aosp-g60-g40.4450789/&#34;&gt;xda-developers.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
